# 哈喽大家好 我是王刚
Hello,everyone,I’m WangGang.
# 本期视频我和大家分享一道家常菜
In today’s video I’m gonna share with everybody a homely dish
# 青椒炒荷包蛋
“poached egg fry green pepper“
# 首先我们准备鸡蛋6个
First,prepared six eggs ,
# 鸡蛋不用打开清点数量备用即可
we needn’t crack eggs,just count the number of eggs for later use.
# 下一步开始准备辅料
Next,prepare the minor ingredients.
# 准备二荆条6个去掉辣椒蒂之后切成小粒备用
Dice six "Erjingtiao" chili pepper for later use,
# 不能吃辣的同学可以用大青椒替换
if you can’t eat spicily ,you can replace it with green bell pepper.
# 准备小半个大红椒切成小粒备用
Dice a half red bell pepper for later use,
# 加红椒的目的是配色
the purpose of adding red bell pepper is to match colors.
# 准备大葱1根从中间切开之后切成小粒备用
spring onions are split in half and dice it for later use.
# 此菜属于急火爆炒
This dish need to fry on high heat,
# 所以必须将大葱中间改刀切
so we must cut spring onions in the middle,
# 最后准备大蒜3颗拍散之后剁碎备用
finally cut garlic into small pieces for later use.
# 下一步开始制作
Next we start cooking.
# 首先我们把锅烧热
First heat the wok,
# 锅烧热之后加入适量的底油滑锅
after the wok was heated,add some base oil to grease the wok,
# 滑好锅之后将热油到出
Pour out hot oil after greasing wok,
# 然后直接打入鸡蛋煎至两面金黄
directly whip eggs into wok and fry eggs until golden,
# 同学们切记煎蛋必须小火慢煎
Remember fry eggs must use soft fire to fry,
# 锅中且不能有生水否则必粘
there must be no unboiled water in the wok,
# 待鸡蛋完全定型之后开始轻轻晃动铁锅
when eggs fried to fixed shape,
# 然后将其翻过来继续兼职金黄
then fry another side until golden,
# 将剩余的5个鸡蛋按照此法煎制
The remaining five eggs are made the same way.
# 下一步开始炒制
Next we start frying.
# 鸡蛋到出之后加入少许底油烧热
Add some base oil when pour out eggs.
# 油温烧热之后将准备好的青椒以及辅料全部下锅
add in all other ingredients.
# 然后转大火将青椒翻炒出大量锅气且炒至断生
Turn into big fire,continue stir-fry green bell pepper until a bring out the Wok-hei and softened.
# 青椒断生之后开始调味
Then we start to seasoning.
# 锅中加入食用盐1勺（约2克）
Add in 2 grams of salt,
# 加入少许白糖提鲜
a pinch of sugar,
# 加入少许鸡精
a pinch of chicken flavoring,
# 加入生抽酱油5克从锅边淋入
then add 5 grams of light soy sauce along the side of the wok,toss evenly.
# 然后加入少许明油从锅边淋入
Then add in some Ming You (literally "brightening oil") along the side of the wok,
# 最后加入煎好的鸡蛋下锅
lastly add in fried eggs,
# 然后关火翻炒均匀即可出锅装盘
then turn off fire toss and stir-fry.now it’s ready to be set on plate.
# 一道非常美味的青椒炒荷包蛋就制作完成
A very delicious poached egg fry green pepper was completed.
# 下面开始技术总结
The technical summaries are as follow
# 第一，此菜非常简单，特别适合新手操作
First,the method which cook this dish is very easy,so it’s perfect for novices.
# 第二，不能吃辣的同学可以选择其它种类的辣椒
Second,if you cannot eat spicy,you can pick other kind chili.
# 第三，最后关火翻炒的目的是防止辣椒的香味丢失
Third,lastly turn off the fire and stir-fry is aimed to prevent the loss of the scent of chili peppers.
# 青椒炒荷包蛋的技术总结完毕